Inkyu Shin | Curriculum Vitae

☑ dlsrbgg33@kaist.ac.kr

I am a third-year Ph.D. student at Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) under the co-supervision of Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon and Prof. In So Kweon. I earned my B.S and M.S degrees in automotive engineering from Hanyang University(HYU) and KAIST in 2019 and 2021. I interned at NEC Laboratories America, Inc, San Jose, CA (with Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai), and Google Research (with Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen and Dr. Jun Xie). I am currently engaged in a research internship at TikTok.

Research Interests

My research is dedicated to establishing a robust foundation in the field of computer vision. This endeavor focuses on pioneering advancements in beyond or human-level visual **generation** and **recognition**, while pursuing the **data-efficiency** for generalizability. Specifically, I am interested in the following research topics:

o Learning for Generative AI

Video Generation / Editing

o Learning for Visual Recognition

Image Segmentation Video Segmentation Multi Object Tracking

Learning for Data-efficiency

Learning from Simulation Domain Adaptation Unsupervised Learning Self-supervised Learning

but also open to other explorable/challenging domains.

The ultimate purpose of these researches is to apply to a variety of applications (e.g., Autonomous driving, Robot Navigation, AR/VR).

Research Experience

 ByteDance / TikTok Research Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Qihang Yu Topic: Video Generation / Editing 	San Jose, CA Sep 5 - Current
Google Research Student Researcher Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Jun Xie - Topic: Video Recognition / Tracking	LA, CA (virtual) May 2022 - April 2023
NEC Laboratories America, Inc Research Intern, Mentor: Yi-Hsuan Tsai - Topic: Test-time Adaptation	San Jose, CA (virtual) May 2021 - Aug 2021
 Korea University Research Intern, Supervisor: Jaegul Choo Topic: Image-to-Image Translation 	Seoul, Korea Sep 2018 - Dec 2018
Hanyang University Research Assistant, Supervisor: Myuong-Ho Sunwoo	Seoul, Korea Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

Future Vehicle Ph.D. degree, Co-Advisors: Kuk-Jin Yoon and In So Kweon

2021-

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

Future Vehicle M.S degree, Advisor: In So Kweon

2019-2021

Master's Thesis: Learning to Scale the Labels for Self-training based Domain Adaptation

Hanyang University (HYU)

Seoul, Korea

AUTOMOTIVE ENGINEERING B.S degree

2013-2019

Publications

(C: conference / J: journal / P: preprint / * :equal contributions)

International Conference.....

o [C13] Video-kMaX: A Simple Unified Approach for Online and Near-Online Video Panoptic Segmentation

Inkyu Shin, Dahun Kim, Qihang Yu, Jun Xie, Hong-Seok Kim, Bradley Green, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Liang-Chieh Chen

Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2024 (Oral)

- Also presented at "Transformer For Vision" Workshops in conjuction with "CVPR, 2023

 [C12] MATE: Masked Autoencoders are Online 3D Test-Time Learners Muhammad Jehanzeb Mirza*, Inkyu Shin*, Wei Lin*, Andreas Schriebl, Kunyang Sun, Jaesung Choe, Horst Possegger, Mateusz Kozinski, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Horst Bischof ICCV, 2023

o [C11] TTA-COPE: Test-Time Adaptation for Category-Level Object Pose Estimation Taeyeop Lee, Jonathan Tremblay, Valts Blukis, Bowen Wen, Byeong-Uk Lee, Inkyu Shin, Stan Birchfield, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023

- o [C10] Bidirectional Domain Mixup for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation Daehan Kim*, Minseok Seo*, Kwanyong Park, Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023
- o [C9] Learning Classifiers of Prototypes and Reciprocal Points for Universal Domain Adaptation Sungsu Hur, Inkyu Shin, Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon Winter Conference on Computer Vision (WACV), 2023
- o [C8] Moving from 2D to 3D: volumetric medical image classification for rectal cancer staging Joohyung Lee*, Jieun Oh*, **Inkyu Shin**, You-sung Kim, Dae Kyung Sohn, Tae-sung Kim, In So Kweon Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2023
- o [C7] MM-TTA: Multi-Modal Test-Time Adaptation for 3D Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Yi-Hsuan Tsai, Bingbing Zhuang, Samuel Schulter, Buyu Liu, Sparsh Garg, In So Kweon,

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022

- Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2022.
- o [C6] UDA-COPE: Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Category-level Object Pose Estimation

Taeyeop Lee, Byeong-Uk Lee, **Inkyu Shin**, Jaesung Choe, Ukcheol Shin, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (**CVPR**), 2022

- [P2] Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Video Semantic Segmentation Kwanyong Park*, Inkyu Shin*, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon arXiv, 2021
- [C5] LabOR: Labeling Only if Required for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Dong-Jin Kim, Jae Won Cho, Sanghyun Woo, Kwanyong Park, In So Kweon International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021 (Oral)
 - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.
- [P1] Learning Representations by Contrasting Clusters While Bootstrapping Instances
 Junsoo Lee, Hojoon Lee, Inkyu Shin, Jaekyoung Bae, In So Kweon, Jaegul Choo
 arXiv, 2020
- [C4] Discover, Hallucinate, and Adapt:
 Open Compound Domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation
 Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, Inkyu Shin, In So Kweon
 Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

 Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.
- [C3] Two-phase Pseudo Label Densification for Self-training based Domain Adaptation Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo, Fei pan, In So Kweon European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020
 Also presented at "Visual Learning with Limited Labels" Workshops in conjunction with (CVPR), 2020
- [C2] Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision
 Fei pan, Inkyu Shin, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon
 Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020 (Oral)
 - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2020.
- [C1] Image-to-Image Translation via Group-wise Deep Whitening-and-Coloring Transformation Wonwoong Cho, Sungha Choi, David Keetae Park, Inkyu Shin, Jaegul Choo Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019 (Oral)

Awards

2022: Qualcomm Innovation Award2021: Qualcomm Innovation Award2020: Qualcomm Innovation Award

IT skills

- Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, LATEX
- o Libraries: PyTorch, TensorFlow

References

o Prof. In So Kweon

Relationship: M.S & Ph.D Advisor

Professor, Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Email: iskweon77@kaist.ac.kr

o Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon

Relationship: Ph.D Advisor

Professor, Mechanical Engineering, KAIST

Email: kjyoon@kaist.ac.kr

o Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai

Relationship: Internship mentor at NEC Lab. (Previous) Research scientist, NEC Lab. (Current) AI/ML Tech Lead Manager, Google

Email: wasidennis@gmail.com

o Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen

Relationship: Internship mentor at Google Research / ByteDance $\,$

 $({\sf Previous}) \ {\sf Research} \ {\sf scientist}, \ {\sf Google} \ {\sf Research}$

(Current) Research scientist, ByteDance

Email: lcchen@cs.ucla.edu